[Singing]
[SINGING]
[NON-ENGLISH SINGING]
(speaking in foreign language)
[SINGING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Something of the Cooper today, we
center on one word used in Quran, the word, this is Arabic, just in Jesus. This percentage of you will want to speak. Take it for what it is, word, and get something out of it, and how to do that.
You think, and all that, but you know why, and you know an alternative?
Two, I have to do this.
But actually, many of you said here, it's not mine.
You just come from my studies of geology years ago, and then,
depending on my memory, it's not so good anymore.
It's good to forget many things, too.
but the conclusion certainly is mine,
and it's offered to you for your consideration.
You work in jail in the Koran of course.
At least where that, I'm not sure if it's number,
but at least maybe it's like more.
It is used in various senses and in various contexts.
For example, in at least four verses,
it is directly connected with Jesus Christ, Jesus is of immorriene.
And I will read to you some of these verses.
I'm using the translation of the Star-Starington.
First verse, "God endowed him with very good reason,
with scripture, wisdom, with Torah, and with gospel."
The word gospel is a translation of the word and in Jesus.
Second, I quote again, this is our surah 3 verse 48.
Now we go to surah 5 verse 46.
Subsequent to them, that is, other prophets,
We sent Jesus the son of Mary, confirming the previously revealed Torah.
We gave him the gospel as in jail containing guidance and light,
and confirming the Torah, as well as providing guidance,
and enlightenment for the righteous, two or five, forty cities.
And one more.
Subsequent to them, that is, Noah, the Brelim,
and some of the descendants, and that says,
subsequent to them, we sent other messengers.
Then we sent Jesus' design of Mary.
We gave him the gospel, the Injil,
and we placed in the hearts of his followers,
time, mess, and mercy.
Now there are about four or five of these.
One of the last says, he gave,
"Risan, be in Jesus."
Now, I pray for all of you,
we need a little attention and connotating of this,
so hold this understanding.
Four or five times, as I said,
that we, for us, have given Jesus' son of Mariam,
And this is what we are going to do this afternoon,
shall have to concentrate on the meaning of a gene.
But I want you now, there are other verses in the Quran
which uses the word "in gene" in a slightly different sense,
How did you do?
In Surah 5, 47, Allah speaks of the people of the gospel.
That's something else, right?
The people of the gospel.
This would refer therefore to the followers of Christ or to the Christians.
Also, in Surah 7 verse 157, there is a suggestion of something being written into the Lord and
in the gospel.
So this is what I am making all of you.
While I am talking all the time of the four original verses or initial verses or something
given to Israel, that the safety mind that Quran speaks of a written gospel and also of
people found in the gospel. But for our present purposes, we are only going to concentrate
on those four or five verses which says that Allah gave the Israel to Jesus.
All right.
You can see immediately
the Quran comes in the six century or latter part of the 17th. All right?
The Quran has come historically
and the Christians were around for more than 500 years.
About 300 years, I don't remember how to accept now, they, about 300 years before, the
third of, "Haysa, Di'Marian," there was a very big colony of Jews in Alexandria, in
Egypt.
They were all what you call members of the Hellenistic
civilization.
And they had forgotten Hebrew.
And because it's forgotten Hebrew and they wanted to know
their spiritual, it was necessary to translate the Hebrew
Bible into Greek.
That is the famous of the so-called Septuagint, which you heard.
The Septuagint, you heard Septuagint, Septuagint, 17, because according to the division, there were 70 learned men, long-butes, who were able to translate it into Greek.
Because Jews had forgotten Hebrew,
When you greet an Egypt, every counterpart of the Greek and part later on, the autonomy, everybody was speaking.
The war was already used in deception at least 200 years before that.
And this is the war.
"O Angelion," "O Angelion," that's a good word.
This is classical Greek.
You want "Uru" means good, all right?
That's not it.
Then "Angelion" comes from "Angelion" means to bring news.
Therefore, who and the young in Greek means to bring good news?
And when the Prophet, Isaiah, was saying, we are waiting for the good news, and you know,
in one of the Prophet, Isaiah, the word was already in this word, and so on.
So you can see it's a very old word in classical Greek.
Also found in common Greek word, the coining. Coining is the Greek, the slum.
You can see the roots, all right?
And anyone?
And here, all right?
It is also in Arabic, right?
It's three roots, N, J, N.
In the Arabs, I mean, classical Arabic has no G,
only has J, unless you're a good Egyptian,
then you'll always say, instead of Yama, Yama, Yama.
But that's Egyptian, G is Egyptian.
Arabic has no G.
It uses J or a Heng.
So, then, as most of you know, same general after another couple of hundred years after
translated the Greek Bible, the Septogen into Latin.
This was now just the time of the Roman Empire, and that is called the Latin Vulgate.
Vulgate means common, the vulgar edition.
And the word you is this one, a banjai ji.
You see, you say, all right?
Okay.
Let us, when the books of the new Testament, we have to start to say the wrong, when the
Also, the New Testament were later on, translated into English.
Then there were two words used for good news or for good tidings.
Evangel, which is found in any dictionary, this is a good English word.
Evangel.
And the one who writes or pushes the banjo is called an evangelist, right?
And all the Roman sandwiches like Romanian, Italian, and Spanish, up to now, use the word
evangelist or the Spanish, a banjo.
And one who writes is called a banjoista.
But for some reason or another, the English people did not just use this word, although
they say good English word on the derived from the Greek through the Latin, they used
the word gospel.
Now, the word gospel is a very good English word based on unglossaxo.
It is God's spell, not God, God in the sense of good.
Back in touch, G-O-E-D, good, it's not God, it is good.
So, good spell, good spell means good news.
And then they refined it, it became gospel.
So sorry that I've taken so much of you time to explain to you the meaning of your gospel.
It means the same as Ebanjel and it is the same as this one comes from the Lord, this word, this word.
All of this means good news, blood tidings and so on.
Now let's go deeper into something matter.
After the death of Jesus Christ, there were many stories about his life.
His life, his work, his death, and his teachings.
And about thirty-four, fifty-sixth, one hundred years after his death, there were many stories about him.
They were not called ghost parents.
They were called memoirs, stories by the apostles.
But because these four of the good news, they became to be called ghost parents.
And there is the so-called gospel according to Matthew.
Because when this gospel of Saint Matthew existed, people did not call it gospel of Saint Matthew.
They said that is the narrative which we believe is from Matthew.
Then you have the mark, loop and jump.
And John, these are the so-called gospel, four gospel.
The first three, as you know, is just a reminder for some of you
who have a good Christian battle to remind.
That these three are called the synoptic gospel,
they're called synoptic, because they talk about the life
of Jesus from birth to death.
And they're very similar.
That one of John is something else.
It has no theology.
What is interesting are the discussions
of different biblical scholars.
There's many theories about it.
I would want to go deep into it because it's
slightly out of our subject.
But it means, I say, that in the old days,
people used to put Machuos number one,
because they thought it was the modern.
Some now say it's smart.
They found out that 70% of Machu
is taken from mark and 70% of blue comes from mark and so on.
There are many theories.
But no, it's already accepted that mark is the oldest.
Now, where the mark was based on an earlier one,
and that earlier one got lost, it's something else.
Or that there was an earlier one from which these three
come from, that's another theory.
It's very important to theory.
Anyhow, it does not bother us to correct theory.
All of it's important for us to know now is that the earliest
manuscripts of this form that we have today are all written in Greek, which many are
my words. But sometimes the are my word or Hebrew word is explained. Therefore very clear.
This was written for people who were written. Somebody says that there was an original Hebrew
gospel which this tree imitated and that is God. Anyhow, again we should not worry about
that. They are all in the earliest manuscripts and the Greek, but with many
alamite words and Hebrew words. It's assumed that the leader knows Greek and
the familiar with his course through the song. But as you know during this time
And they were also at the ghost place.
Now many of these stories in the Quran
that gives the text as a little boy knew what was written
by his friends.
This is found in one of these efforts,
from every memory.
Then about the miracles of the birds,
clay, the carbon, this is found here.
There is what you call the ghost of difference.
Infancy, the ghost of, second ghost of infancy,
is ghost of
And lately, I think within our lifetime,
they have discovered in Egypt the gospel of Saint Thomas.
Now, the importance of this gospel of Saint Thomas
is that in Copic, it has the sayings of Jesus Christ.
Some found in this gospel some not found.
And many people say that that is the essential message
of this crime, which tends to the ancient Egyptians,
were able to be collected together.
People are still going into this.
But the stung went on by 100 years of the crime.
This became what you call this canonical, accepted as good.
And then this became forgotten.
This was authoritative for many years.
But people say, no, not so good as this.
It was forgotten, it became told, it became told,
a folk reform, as you know the work, a folk reform means
hidden, not hidden people hidden, but hidden in the libraries,
hidden in the archives, hidden from the sides of the
political data forget about it.
So these ones are not considered canonical or
accepted among people.
Both stands, the people to go and the Catholics.
But all of these 27 are considered canonical and
the ones that have been done.
OK.
The question now is this.
What does the work in gene mean associated with corral?
It is, as you can see, a word that is arabized.
Not only has it become arabized, but it even
has a very good arabic doula and as in.
But Quran is inherited of the thinking of the past two, and all scholars say, "Please
engineer of the Lord six hundred and a century to play on a world that is hundreds of times
of years of all the people."
So, there are some people, and I feel that the spirit may include, say, no,
they are very rich in Arabs, they say, "Injil comes from Najala."
You go to Arabic, Najala means to throw out something to give, to open a wound, to cross,
but to open a tissue.
And that is the meaning of a spirit also.
And jil, something like Arabic.
[INAUDIBLE]
It's one of these states.
But it seems that these words, the root
[INAUDIBLE]
from all other things is something else.
I think it is generally considered
that when [INAUDIBLE]
it is talking to people who are Christians.
They understand what more people.
Naturally, at that time, there will be people who already know Latin or from Greek.
It will become part of the great
with the dangerous ones.
It's just a good thing to report based on kind of such.
Incidentally, the Christians in Syria, I don't know about the Christians in the ancient
course, I don't know them whether or not, but in Syria, they used to work good news,
When they want to go, they want to go to do what? But they don't want to do what Greek word or the Latin word.
Although they use it sometimes, I know that the Christians will do what in jail.
But when they want to use a typical Arab word, they use "passiro".
Passiro means also good news.
And "takshir" means to preach, or "takshiri" is one who preaches the good news.
This is found in Syria, I don't know what it is.
Also, Bashir means good news.
And to preach the good news is stop Syria, stop Syria,
and forget the good.
Anyhow, but I know that if Pakistan and Syria
don't want to reward Bashir, the Bashir means
it could add a big world.
And you know, Bashir means one of these good news.
Then like this, historical purposes, etc.
Now, the question is this.
What does the word "engines" mean in the first four or five verses that I call that?
It means it means it means it.
I think you don't have to accept this, but just think about it.
That means, Quran says that God has given his answer.
He is in jail.
He only means to me.
This.
He gave his answer a message.
That's why Isha is a messenger.
All right?
He could not have given Isha a book.
You don't give a person a book where you'll
burn and describe, and when you're dying, he's described.
Right?
How can you give a book to someone telling him
that he died on the cross or censure?
OK?
This common sense to me.
I don't think twice about it.
You cannot give a person a book which describes his death.
But you can give him a message which later on was written in a book, okay?
I don't know if this is acceptable to you.
Because if we look at these four ghost birds, it describes the bird, the lion, the wolf,
But it also includes messages, a beautiful one as you all know it is someone of the Mount.
I do not deny that there is a message in this little book.
I am only saying that this is one meaning of the word in Jesus and this is another meaning
of the word in Jesus.
If you don't want to accept my thinking of the mother, let me call a certain person by
the name of Oscar Coleman. Oscar Coleman, this electorate in the University of Sovall is
a very eminent individual scholar. This is what he said. It is only in the year, 150 AD,
It was only in the year 550 AD that the world of Hungarian was used in the sense of book.
So 150 years after the death of Christ, this work began to be used in the sense of book
before that it was not.
And before this, before 150 AD, this was called male arms, narratives, stories of the apostles.
And thus you can see why they say he goes to the according to Machu.
Because Machu is time to explain what was the good news, all right?
You almost time to explain what was the good news.
But the explanation of the good news is also a good news.
You get it?
So now you can see it.
Good news, number one.
Good news, number two.
Good news, number two includes good news, number one.
The word in jail is used in two senses.
And the Quran is very now clear, almost uncanny.
when he speaks of the God gave Jesus a message,
and he speaks of something that is written
containing the message.
Now this is more or less a linguistic analysis and so on.
Now I submit to you therefore that these gospels
in the second sense contain the sermons,
the proverbs, the moral teachings of Christ,
It's a message, it contains a message.
And it's a message that Jesus's group
was bringing to the youth of his time
as well as to gentiles or the non-june.
Again, a few people,
on grass meat, let me call Byron,
one of these fellows of the Jewish people, the Cenarius.
He says, "My God, in the new Testament,
The New Testament says the Gospels do not talk of themselves.
Now he's very testing, huh?
The New Testament is saying the Gospels do not talk of themselves.
They contain the message of Jesus of number two is containing number one.
What he says, the rule of the four books, he says, are not the actual messages.
They contain the message.
Now, this shows a difference between the so-called Indian or the energy in this sense,
with the Quran.
The Quran talks of itself, right?
I just pointed out that now, the Quran says, this is a book, the biblical GitHub.
This is a book.
The Quran also talks about itself.
There is no crookedness in this Quran.
Because there's do not talk of themselves.
Number two, there's not talk of number two.
Number two talks of number one.
I hope I'm not too pedantic or pushing this so much.
And so, and so, let me just mention that,
the people of truth, that I believe that the Qur'an says Allah gave is a message.
It means a good use, good use, good tidings.
But what we now have in history is something written is an attempt to write down this message.
But I would not have given Jesus this because he talks about his death.
Now the question is this.
What is this?
Now we don't have a motor.
Message.
What did the Quran say about him?
And what do these goshfels later on say, "What is this?"
Message.
(silence)
[silence]
(clicking)
[ Pause ]
(silence)
(clicking)
(clapping)
(silence)
(clicking)
[ Pause ]
[ Inaudible ]
All biographical details, some found here, some found there.
I will not go into this now.
But regarding the message itself of people, I'll try to enumerate some of them, arrange them for you,
change them for you, but not necessarily in the sequence of order, but just how they
came to even our type in this, because I was very much in Harry.
But I will mention about 2 or 3.
The first one, this old message, according to the Quran, Jesus always says that there
is one and only one God to whom all worship is due.
And the Quran says, "Your Lord and my Lord," which means the same Lord.
And so stating this, that only Allah is worthy or worthy,
drives himself to saying very clearly that no man is to be worthy.
That is the message.
even if he is a prophet or a messenger.
Therefore, we conclude that this thing or this part of this message of Christ is the
general thing not only of the Quran but of all other prophets.
That the God of people, the God of the prophets is one and only one God, which everybody
of worship and the people who preach these are only human beings.
Nobody can be God except Allah in nature.
That is the Kundalini message found in the Quran.
It's also found here.
Because the Holy Spirit is about worshiping the daily Quran God is all.
Number two, you see that your prevention already,
that number one shows the profits have a certain function.
And, mention particular that it is to confirm previous messages.
This is found on here, where Christ says, "I don't have to destroy the law, but to fulfill it."
safety is found in Torah.
A very important message from the Quran.
Jesus, son of Mary, and precise in the visual responsibility alone, born of nine.
He said that reward of punishment
was due to the achievement of person according to this action.
In brief, Jesus thought that there was a day of judgment.
And this could be gathered from the Holy version to a 3, 657 to a form, 121, so a 3,
to a 3, 6, and 5, 58.
And thus, you can see when the story in the Quran where Jesus will say, "Go Allah."
I don't blame you for what these people have done.
I've already told them, I did it.
But they invented things about me,
they invented things about others.
But they are going to pay for their sins.
But those who are righteous, those who are good,
those who follow the teachings of the Prophet,
those who worship Allah, to man of the other,
these people will make heaven.
That is the theory of salvation.
He used to say, "There is heaven for good people."
What can be better?
He could use them now.
Can you find better news?
Then you say that the men who suffer regulation,
but his spirit in righteousness, he will be judged.
Where can he go to heaven?
Not in the essence or the so-called good youth or good
and so on. And these are those who are righteous, they will deserve paradise. It is good to
They will deserve paradise.
It is good.
How could you learn even a cheque, Daniel and Jim?
You know, speaking of this poem.
I am a whole machine of the name of the humanity.
One machine of the humanity, about the name of what?
[speaking in foreign language]
(speaking in foreign language)
- Angelos is messenger.
Angelos is messenger.
That's why he wants Angel Tamskram.
I think it's good, like here in Indonesia,
if you look at the video for a new genix, new genix.
And then the angel is the message.
To bring the message, we want to enjoy the talk about it.
Not this thing about the answer, because Angela's a message.
Because the angel is the message.
I think that's about anymore.
But then we're in Arabic, the trauma.
Yes, it is a pallet or a palleta
I'm going to go for a moment
Do it!
To give it to him?
Yes, it is a pallet
Because he's in the air, he's in the air
But he's still in the air, but he's still in the air
But they breathe with their forces
They're representing this
They're called Gabriel, who's representing him
But they're selecting because they say the angel band band is here
They make a distillation
It's a distinction
Yeah.
Put your dress down,
leave 'em.
I don't want any flashes in this box.
Thank you very much.
I'm stepping back.
No, I am.
You sure wanna get me?
Yes.
I like it.
It's a pretty place.
It's a pretty nice place.
Very nice.
Sometimes you understand a lot more about anything
and what the word is.
And you don't even know the meaning of the word
of the word from yourself.
It's a pretty nice place.